Greg Simon PhD

gregorygsimon@gmail.com (805) 746-1668

Professional Summary

Experienced faculty in mathematics and statistics. Expertise in practical application and theory of state-of-the-art data analysis, including data wrangling and cleaning, exploratory data analysis, modern statistics and machine learning. Successful projects in general automation, forecasting, classification, regression, image recognition, and natural language processing.

Portfolio available at: https://gregorygsimon.github.io

Education

PhD Mathematics, 2016, University of Michigan.

BA Mathematics, 2010, University of California, Santa Cruz.

• cum laude and highest honors in the major (mathematics)

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, SQL, Spark, Mathematica, R (some), Julia (some)

Other: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Apps Script, Bash/Linux, Docker

Certifications: AWS Certification - Machine Learning Specialty (2020, ID#RX11FD2CEB4E1WKF)

Employment Experience

Western Governors University Course Faculty [2017 – Present]

- Teaching applied statistics to undergraduate and graduate students outstanding student evaluations available upon request
- Led statistical analysis project aligning course practice problems with positive student outcomes
- Department expert in data visualization in Python
- Developed model to predict student success on assessment, used to target student outreach
- Created automation pipeline for department to email messages to students daily
- Maintained dashboard used by department daily to summarize student progress

University of Michigan Graduate Student Instructor [2011-2016], Lecturer [2016-2017]

- Primary instructor for calculus series, including differential equations and multi-variable calculus
- Course coordinator for Accelerated Precalculus (2 terms), Calculus II

Selected Talks and Presentations

Finite Simple Groups: Thirty Years of the Atlas and Beyond, poster session. 11/2015, Princeton. AMS Central Fall Sectional Meeting, Special Session on K-Loops, Near Domains, and Nonassociative Division algebras. 10/2015. Loyola University.

AMS Central Spring Sectional Meeting, Special Session on Groups and Representations, 4/2015. Michigan State University.

Projects and Workshops

Image recognition 6-week project with TrainX 7/2019 – 9/2019

- Co-lead of five student practitioners developing image recognition model in AWS to predict make and models from images of car from greenlight cameras, in connection with Detroit PD
- Contact: Aubrey Agee, TrainX co-founder, aubrey@trainx.ai

Workshop: New Directions in Lie Theory. 2/2014 - 3/2014. Centre de Recherches Mathématiques, Université de Montréal.

updated: Aug 10, 2020